<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Alberto Parmiggiani</title>
    <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://miggia.github.io/it/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>it</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://miggia.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-UU mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/n-uu_mechanisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/n-uu_mechanisms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More recently, our group started directing part of its effort to the study and development of two degrees of freedom (DOF) mechanisms to be employed as robot wrists. As part of these studies, we were the first to report on the asymmetric and anisotropic properties of the workspace of N-UU type mechanisms (a.k.a. OmniWrist III type mechanisms). The main findings of this work were presented in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shah, D., Metta, G., &amp;amp; Parmiggiani, A. (2018). Workspace analysis and the effect of geometric parameters for parallel mechanisms of the N-UU class. In ASME Int. Conf. on Design Engineering - IDETC/CIE. Quebec City, Canada: American Society of Mechanical Engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R1</title>
      <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/r1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/r1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The years 2015 and 2016 were entirely devoted to a new project, strongly endorsed by the scientific direction of IIT. The ambitious aim of the project was to design, build and demonstrate a robot functionally equivalent to the iCub humanoid but at one-twentieth (&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt;) of the cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goal was pursued with a design-for-manufacturing approach, novel solutions for robot mechanisms, and by a wide use of polymeric materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was of a rather large scale, involving over 30 people working in 7 different institutions in different geographical locations (Italy, Spain, Switzerland and New Zealand). The total budget of the project was around 1.1M€ (including personnel, consumables, and external services).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this period, I managed the project and acted as the main reference person for all development related issues. As part of my project management duty, I introduced an AGILE working methodology, which largely increased the efficiency and proficiency of the development team. I personally designed several robot sub-assemblies. Over the course of 16 months, we developed from scratch three new types of robotic actuators and a novel motor control methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first prototype of the R1 robot was demonstrated in April 2016. The main results of this project were published in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parmiggiani, A., Fiorio, L., Scalzo, A., Sureshbabu, A. V., Randazzo, M., Maggiali, M., … Metta, G. (2017). The design and validation of the R1 personal humanoid. In IEEE/RSJ Int. Conf. on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). DOI: 10.1109/IROS.2017.8202224&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- The R1 represents an attempt to bring the iCub technology closer to real world applications, and was specially focused on making the robot system affordable.

The key ingredients to achieve this goal were the extensive use of engineering plastics, parallel kinematics, and of a design for manufacturing approach.

An introductory video about the robot can be found [here](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TBphNGW6m4o). --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iCub expressive face</title>
      <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/icub_expressive_face/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/icub_expressive_face/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the various sub-systems that I developed for the iCub robot was an articulated talking face developed jointly with Prof. Gerard Bailly and Dr Frederic Elisei at the University of Grenoble. The head featured an articulated jaw and four independent lip movements actuated by five motors. The head was covered by a specially designed elastic tissue cover whose hemlines at the lips are attached to the motors via connecting linkages. This variant of the iCub head was later employed for psychometric studies on the perception of speech. The main results of this work were published in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parmiggiani, A., Randazzo, M., Maggiali, M., Metta, G., Elisei, F., &amp;amp; Bailly, G. (2015). Design and validation of a talking face for the iCub. International Journal of Humanoid Robotics, DOI:10.1142/S0219843615500267&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iCub SEA legs</title>
      <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/icub_sea_legs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/icub_sea_legs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2012 I completed the new design of the legs of the iCub robot. This project was the result of a collaboration with colleagues of the Advanced Robotics department at IIT. The most relevant new feature of the system was the addition of series elastic actuators (SEA). The original SEA design was adapted and optimized through the development of a custom spring based on the curved beam concept. SEA were later used for comparative studies on stiff and compliant robot actuation. A description of the system is presented in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parmiggiani, A., Metta, G., &amp;amp; Tsagarakis, N. (2012). The mechatronic design of the new legs of the iCub robot. In IEEE-RAS Int. Conf. on Humanoid Robots (HUMANOIDS) (pp. 481–486). DOI: 10.1109/HUMANOIDS.2012.6651563&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iCub2</title>
      <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/icub2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/icub2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Between 2010 and 2011 I focused on the development of several hardware modules that laid the basis for the mechanics of the second version of the iCub robot (iCub2). Besides the original design work, I integrated advanced sensing solutions developed by colleagues specializing in micro-electronics. The new version of the robot integrated an improved system for the position sensing of the electric motor rotors, field oriented control for the brushless DC motors, additional acceleration and angular velocity MEMS sensors, and a full-body skin with approximately 4000 independent pressure measurement points. A detailed description of the results of the project is presented in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parmiggiani, A., Maggiali, M., Natale, L., Nori, F., Schmitz, A., Tsagarakis, N., … Metta, G. (2012). The design of the iCub humanoid robot. International Journal of Humanoid Robotics, 9. DOI: 10.1142/S0219843612500272&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
