<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>robotics | Alberto Parmiggiani</title>
    <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/tag/robotics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://miggia.github.io/it/tag/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>robotics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>it</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://miggia.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>robotics</title>
      <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/tag/robotics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>R1</title>
      <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/r1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/r1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of the R1 project was to bring the technology developed in the iCub project one step closer to the market. This problem was addressed with a design-for-manufacturing approach, novel solutions for robot mechanisms, and by a wide use of polymeric materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was of a rather large scale, involving over 30 people working in 7 different institutions in different geographical locations (Italy, Spain, Switzerland and New Zealand). The total budget of the project was around 1.1M€ (including personnel, consumables, and external services).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first complete robot prototype was demonstrated in April 2016, just 16 months after the beginning of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iCub</title>
      <link>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/icub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miggia.github.io/it/project/icub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The iCub is a 53DOF open-source humanoid robot. Since 2007 In the years from 2007 to 2019 I have been heavily involved in the design and testing of several of its parts. Among these, the upper-body, the legs, the six-axis force-torque sensors, the covers, the legs, the hands and forearms, and the head. Since 2010, until September 2019 I have served the role of hardware lead of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details about the robot can be found on the project website: &lt;a href=&#34;www.icub.org&#34;&gt;www.icub.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
